{"title": "NoSQL", "questions": [{"question": "Q1. Which types of indexes are available in CosmosDB?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " range and spatial\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " secondary and primary key\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " secondary and spatial\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " range and primary key\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q2. You want to connect a DynamoDB stream to AWS Lambda function. Which one of these object do you create?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " DynamoDB table\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB trigger\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB item\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB index\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q3. To index a field that holds an array value in MongoDB, which index type do you create?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " partial\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " sparse\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " compound\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " multikey\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q4. You want to test HBASE on your laptop using the fewest number of steps. What do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Set up Hadoop in pseudo-distributed mode.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Set up HBASE in local mode.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Set up HBASE in pseudo-distributed mode.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Set up Hadoop in local mode.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q5. You need to create a document database that supports database triggers. Which NoSQL database should you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " DynamoDB\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " BigTable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Redis\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MongoDB\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q6. What is recommended size for Redis keys?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " medium\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " short\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " single bit\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " long\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q7. What does Redis use to sort the elements of a sorted set?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Scores\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Ids\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Values\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Keys\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q8. You need to change the shard key of an existing MongoDB collection. What do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Dump the collection data, drop the collection, create a new collection and shard key, import the data.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Add second shard key and drop the first shard key.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Dump the collection data, drop the collection, presplit the data, create a new collection and shard key, import the data.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Drop and recreate the shard key.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q9. Polyglot storage means using multiple types of what in the same application?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Security systems\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Database systems\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Storage systems\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Query systems\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q10. You need to implement the simplest possible scalable, in-memory cache for your AWS application. Which service do you select?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Elasticache using Memcached.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX).\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Elasticache using Redis.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q11. You are doing data modelling for Google BigTable. Which statement expresses if and when you should split entities across multiple rows?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Keep all information for an entity in a single row. Store related entities in adjacent rows.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Keep all information for an entity in a single row.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Split entities across multiple rows if the entity data is over thousands of MBs, or if it does not need atomic updates and reads.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Split entities across multiple rows if the entity data is over hundreds of MBs, or if it does not need atomic updates and reads.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q12. Which two characteristics define Amazon Quantum Ledger Database?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Key-value data model; transactionally consistent with ACID semantics.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Document data model; transactionally consistent with ACID semantics.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Key-value data model; transactions with tunable consistency.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Document data model; transactions with tunable consistency.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q13. You need to design the primary key for DynamoDB based on three attributes. What do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Designate all three fields as the primary key.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Concatenate all three fields into one new field, then designate that new field as the primary key.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Designate two fields of the three fields as the primary key.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Concatenate two fields into one new field, then designate that new field and the remaining field as the primary key.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q14. Which of these data types should you avoid in designing a Google Bigtable row key?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " multi-valued identifiers\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " string identifiers\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " timestamps\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " frequently updated identifiers\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q15. Your startup is building a prototype that has an evolving schema. Your data will be eventually consistent. Your application is hosted in AWS. Which database do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Neptune\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DocumentDB\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Amazon Aurora\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q16. You need to create a scalable database that allows you to share documents across authorized mobile clients in real time. What Google NoSQL database should you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Memorystore\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Datastore\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Firebase\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Bigtable\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q17. You need to design security for DynamoDB to allow users read-only access to certain items and attributes in a table. What do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Use IAM roles.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use IAM policy conditions.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Use a VPC endpoint.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use IAM policies.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q18. Which statement is preferred Cypher code for Neo4j?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " MATCH (:Person)--&gt;(:Card)--&gt;(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Match (:Person)--&gt;(:Car):(vehicle:Car)--&gt;(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MATCH (:Person)--&gt;(vehicle:Car)--&gt;(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " MATCH (:Person)--&gt;(:Card), (vehicle:Car)--&gt;(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q19. You need multi-item ACID transactions with snapshot isolation within a partition for your cloud-based application. Which NoSQL databse do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Bigtable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " GraphDB\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " DynamoDB\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Cosmos DB\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q20. You need to control your application's batch updates destination for your Bigtable multinode cluster. Which action do you take?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Create a custom app profile to route batch updates.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Create a custom app profile to route the batch update from that client.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Update the default app profile to route the natch update from that client.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Use the default app profile to route batch updates.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q21. Your query to verify that your Redis key is configured to support expiring user information on a defined interval returns -2, What does this value indicate?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " The queried key value expired in the last two seconds.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " The queried key value exists, but has no associated expire value.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " The queried key value does not exist.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " There are two expired keys with this value.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q22. You are designing a MongoDB schema to support queries that will include lookups. What should you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Create an index on the key value used as the primary key.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Create an index on the key value used as the foreign key.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Create a multicolumn index on the key value used as the foreign key and the most unique column in the document.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Create a multicolumn index on the key value used as the primary and also the foreign key.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q23. What is the aggregation operator for a join concept in MongoDB?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " \\$group\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " \\$match\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " \\$lookup\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " \\$project\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q24. For your mobile application, you need to select a Google cloud database that can support compound, filtered document queries. Which do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Cloud SQL\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Cloud Spanner\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Cloud Firestore\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Cloud Firebase\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q25. To bulk load data into Amazon Neptune, what do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Upload data to S3 VPC endpoint, Use the Neptune loader to load from s3 into your Neptune instance\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Ad data to a Kinesis stream, and use the Neptune loader to load from S# into your Neptune instance.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Add data to a Kinesis stream, and create a Kinesis stream VPC endpoint. Use the Neptune loader to load from S3 into your Neptune instance.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Upload data to S Use the Neptune loader to load from S3 into your Neptune instance.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q26. You need to create a pub/sub server. Which database do you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Neo4j\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Cassandra\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Redis\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " MyS#### QL\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q27. SQL databases and NoSQL are which types of scalable?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " horizontally, infinitely\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " vertically, horizontally\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " vertically, infinitely\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " horizontally, vertically\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q28. You need to create a scalable database that allows you to query data nodes and edges efficiently. What do you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " a relational database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a columnstore database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a document database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a graph database\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q29. You are developing a model for a graph database. Your data will be moved from a relational database into Neo4j. Which of these transformations apply?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Rows become labels: bales become nodes.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Tables become labels: rows become nodes.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " Tables become collections: rows become items.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Rows become collections: tables become items.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q30. You need to execute a command for MongoDB that does NOT load values from the <code>.mongorc.js</code> file. What do you do ?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Delete the .monorc.js file and restart mongo shell.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use the mongo shell to create a command with --norc option\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Rem all lines in the .mongorc.js file ad restart mongo shell.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use the mongo shell to create a command with --nodedefault option.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q31. You need to store an unordered collection of name-value pairs with differing data types in DynamoDB. Which data type should you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " map\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " set\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " list\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " stack\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q32. Which statement retrieves an item from the MusicCollection table in DynamoDB?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " aws dynamodb query --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " aws dynamodb get-item --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " aws dynamodb select --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " aws dynamodb put-item --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q33. Database availability is measured by which metric?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " the amount of service calls\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " the number of minutes\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " the amount of service costs\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " the number of nines\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q34. You need to encrypt data at rest in DynamoDB. Which action do you take?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " You assign a default AWS encryption key to your table to encrypt data.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " You create an AWS encryption key and assign it to your table to encrypt data.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " None. Data is encrypted by default.\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " You create an AWS encryption key and assign it to your database to encrypt data.\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q35. You need to generate a unique, sequential identifier for each value stored in a Redis cluster. What do you do?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Implement a SortedSet object to generate a value.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use the GUID keyword to generate a value.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Implement a List object to generate a value.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Use the INCR keyword to generate a value\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q36. You want to return a list of all elements in two Redis sets. Which keyword do you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " smembers\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " returnall\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " sunion\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " sismember\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q37. Which method shows you whether MongoDB uses any indexes when running a query, and how the indexes are used?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " detailQueryExecution()\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " showPlan()\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " explain()\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " describe()\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q38. Which statement accurately describes global secondary indexes in DynamoDB?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are transactionally consistent, and are guaranteed to return correct results.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are partially consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are eventually consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.\n</ul>\n<p><a href=\"https://stackoverflow.com/questions/35414372/dynamodb-consistent-reads-for-global-secondary-index\">reference link:</a></p>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q39. Which command do you use to add a value to a Redis stream named mystream?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " ADD mystream * sensor-id 1234 temperature 19.8 1518951480106-1\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " UPDATE mystream * sensor-id 1234 temperature 19.8 1518951480106-3\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " XADD mystream * sensor-id 1234 temperature 9.8 1518951480106-0\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " INSERT mystream * sensor-d 1234 temperature 19.8 15181480106-2\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q40. Which code example completes this statement and creates an index for a MongoDB object named restaurants, sorted ascending by the field name?\n<p><code>var indexCollection = function(db) {return co(function*() {...});};</code></p>\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " <code>const results = yield db.table('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 1}, null); return results;</code>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " <code>const results = yield db.collection('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 0}, null); return results;</code>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " <code>const results = yield db.collection('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 1}, null); return results;</code>\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " <code>const results = yield db.table('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 0}, null); return results;</code>\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q41. Which Cypher code executes the multiquery block?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " A\n</ul>\n<p><code>MATCH (c:Company {name: 'Neo4j'}) RETURN c, MATCH (p:Person) WHERE p.name = 'Jennifer' RETURN p,\nMATCH (t:Technology)-[:LIKES]-(a:Person {name: 'Jennifer'}) RETURN t.type;</code></p>\n<ul>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " B\n</ul>\n<p><code>MATCH (c:Company {name: 'Neo4j'}) RETURN c, MATCH (p:Person) WHERE p.name = 'Jennifer' RETURN p,\nMATCH (t:Technology)-[:LIKES]-(a:Person {name: 'Jennifer'}) RETURN t.type</code></p>\n<ul>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " C\n</ul>\n<p><code>MATCH (c:Company {name: 'Neo4j'}) RETURN c AND MATCH (p:Person) WHERE p.name = 'Jennifer' RETURN p,\nAND MATCH (t:Technology)-[:LIKES]-(a:Person {name: 'Jennifer'}) RETURN t.type;</code></p>\n<ul>\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " D\n</ul>\n<p><code>MATCH (c:Company {name: 'Neo4j'}) RETURN c;MATCH (p:Person) WHERE p.name = 'Jennifer' RETURN p;\nMATCH (t:Technology)-[:LIKES]-(a:Person {name: 'Jennifer'}) RETURN t.type;</code></p>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q42. You need to create a scalable database that supports immutable writes. What do you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " A ledger database\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " A graph database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " A key-value database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " A columnstore database\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q43. You need to create a data store for the catalog for your new ecommerce application. Your company is a startup, so the catalog schema may evolve. Which do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Neo4j\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Redis\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MySQL\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " MongoDB\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q44. You need to select a NoSQL database for heavy aggregate query workloads. Which type do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " graph\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " key-value\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " document\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " columnstore\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": true}]}, {"question": "Q45. You need to select a columnstore database that enforce built-in data types. You want to add indexes to improve performance for known workloads. Which do you choose?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " Cassandra\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Bigtable\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Redis\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " HBase\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q46. In DynamoDB, the partition key and sort key are also known as which type of attributes?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " range, hash\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " primary, range\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " hash, range\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " range, secondary\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q47. What is a popular, open-source key-value store database?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " MongoDB\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Redis\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " MySQL\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " Cassandra\n</ul>\n", "is_correct": false}]}, {"question": "Q48. You need to create a scalable database to store and query JSON data. What do you use?\n", "alternatives": [{"alternative": " a relational database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a document database\n", "is_correct": true}, {"alternative": " a graph database\n", "is_correct": false}, {"alternative": " a ledger database\n</ul>\n<p><a href=\"https://aws.amazon.com/nosql/document/#:~:text=The%20document%20database%20defined,use%20in%20their%20application%20code.\">store and query JSON</a></p>", "is_correct": false}]}]}